Yixin Zou

Address 105 S State St

Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

Mobile Phone Email +1 (773)818-7109 yixinz@umich.edu

Research Interest

My research focuses on the intersection of privacy, security, and human-computer interaction, understanding people's attitude and behavior, and providing actionable guidance that motivates people to take action in face of threats. I also have a particular interest on designing privacy and security solutions for underrepresented and marginalized populations.

Education

Exp. 2022 Ph.D. in Information, University of Michigan

Advisor: Dr. Florian Schaub

2017 B.S. in Advertising, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (UIUC)

Graduated with the Highest Honor (top 5% in the college)

Honors and Awards

[H3] SIGCHI Honorable Mention Award (Best Paper Nominee)

Putting Your Warning Where Your Link Is: Improving and Evaluating Email Phishing Warnings, with J. Petelka and F. Schaub. 2019.

- [H2] **USENIX Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS) Distinguished Paper Award** "T've Got Nothing to Lose": Consumers' Risk Perceptions and Protective Actions after the Equifax Data Breach, with A. H. Mhaidli, A. McCall, and F. Schaub. 2018.
- [H1] UMSI Pre-candidacy Paper Distinction Award

Awarded by the University of Michigan School of Information for successful completion of the milestone. The award is given to top 10% of students in this endeavor in any given year.

Fellowships

[F2] Symantec Research Labs Graduate Fellowship

Symantec, \$20,000, 2019-2020. (1 of 3 recipients selected worldwide)

[F1] Annual Fund Scholarship

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign College of Media, \$2,000, 2016-2017.

Grants

- [G4] **SIGCHI Student Travel Grant**, ACM SIGCHI, \$1,800, 2019.
- [G3] **SOUPS Student Grant**, USENIX, \$695, 2018.
- [G2] UMSI PhD Travel Grant, University of Michigan School of Information, \$1,000, 2018-2019.
- [G1] Rackham Conference Travel Grant, University of Michigan Rackham Graduate School, \$1,000, 2018.

Publications

Journal & Magazine Publications

[J1] **Beyond Mandatory: Making Data Breach Notifications Useful for Consumers** Zou, Y., & Schaub, F. *IEEE Security & Privacy*, 17(2), 67-72. [link]

Conference Publications

- [C6] An Empirical Analysis of Data Deletion and Opt-Out Choices on 150 Websites

 Habib H., Zou, Y., Jannu A., Sridhar N., Swoopes C., Acquisti A., Cranor L. F., Sadeh N., & Schaub,
 F. In Proceedings of the 2019 USENIX Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS '19).

 Acceptance Rate: 22.7%. [link]
- [C5] "We Can't Live Without them!" App Developers' Adoption of Ad Networks and Their Considerations of Consumer Risks

Mhaidli A. H., <u>Zou, Y.</u>, & Schaub, F. In Proceedings of the 2019 USENIX Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (**SOUPS '19**). *Acceptance Rate: 22.7%*. [link]

- [C4] You 'Might' Be Affected: An Empirical Analysis of Readability and Usability Issues in Data Breach Notifications
 - Zou, Y., Danino, S., Sun, K., & Schaub, F. In Proceedings of the 2019 ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (**CHI'19**). *Acceptance Rate: 23.8%*. [link]
- [C3] **Put Your Warning Where Your Link Is: Improving and Evaluating Email Phishing Warnings** Petelka, J., <u>Zou, Y.</u>, & Schaub, F. In Proceedings of the 2019 ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (**CHI '19**). *Acceptance Rate: 23.8%*. [link]
- [C2] "I've Got Nothing to Lose": Consumers' Risk Perceptions and Protective Actions after the Equifax Data Breach

Zou, Y., Mhaidli, A. H., McCall, A., & Schaub, F. In Proceedings of the 2018 USENIX Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (**SOUPS '18**). *Acceptance Rate: 22.8%*. [link]

[C1] Users' Attitudes towards the "Going Dark" Debate

Addawood, A., Zou, Y., & Bashir, M. In Proceedings of the 2017 International Conference on Applied Human Factors and Ergonomics (AHFE '17). [link]

Highly-Reviewed Workshop and Non-Proceedings Conference Publications

- [W5] An Empirical Analysis of Online Consent and Opt-Out Experiences
 - Habib, H., Zou, Y., Jannu, A., Swoopes, C., Cranor, L. F., & Schaub, F. Paper presented at *the 11th Annual Privacy Law Scholars Conference (PLSC '18)*, Washington D.C., USA, May 30-31.
- [W4] Concern But No Action: Consumers' Reactions to the Equifax Data Breach

Zou, Y. & Schaub, F. In *Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computer Systems (CHI '18) Late Breaking Work*, Montreal, Canada, April 22-26. [link]

[W3] An Empirical Analysis of Website Data Deletion and Opt-Out Choices

Habib, H., Zou, Y., Jannu, A., Swoopes, C., Acquisti, A., Cranor, L. F., Sadeh, N., & Schaub, F. Paper presented at *CHI '18 Workshop "The General Data Protection Regulation, an opportunity for the HCI Community?"*, Montreal, Canada, April 22. [link]

[W2] The Impacts of Privacy Hypocrisy, Victim Characterization, Gender, and Context on Bystanders' Guilt Attribution in a Cyberbullying Suicide

Yao, M., Zou, Y., Linz, D., & Jaoude, P. Paper presented at *the 67th Annual Conference of International Communication Association (ICA)*, San Diego, CA, May 25-29.

[W1] Really Being There?: Telepresence in Virtual Reality Branded Content

Shen, J., Stenger, M., Lechowicz J., Chen C., Yang, R., Sivasankaran, A., Wang Y., Zhang, J., Zou, Y., Katz, H., & Nelson M. R. Paper presented at *the Annual Conference of the Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication (AEJMC)*, Chicago, IL, August 9-12.

Posters

[P1] "I've Got Nothing to Lose": Consumers' Risk Perceptions and Protective Actions after the Equifax Data Breach

Zou, Y., Mhaidli, A. H., McCall, A., & Schaub, F. Poster presented at *the 6th Midwest Security Workshop (MSW6)*, Urbana, IL, April 14.

Employment

05/2019- Symantec Research Labs, Culver City, CA.

08/2019 Symantec Research Labs Intern. *Advisor: Kevin Roundy*.

- Conducted an online survey to examine the adoption and abandonment of recommended practices for security, privacy, and identity theft protection.
- Planned, organized, and ran participatory design workshops to understand how spyware notifications could be improved to combat intimate partner violence.

01/2019- Mozilla Corporation, Mountain View, CA.

04/2019 User Experience Research Intern. *Advisor: Jennifer Davidson.*

- Ran usability testings on wireframe prototypes for Firefox Monitor. Insights were integrated to the product's new site to refine risk communications and design.
- Conducted an online experiment to investigate how content and format impact users' decision to react to data breach notifications.

09/2017- University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI.

Present Graduate Student Research Assistant. *Advisor: Florian Schaub.*

Lead or assist with various research projects related to user interactions with security
and privacy notices and choices. Topics include: examining consumer reactions to data
breaches and issues in breach notifications; developing effective choice mechanisms for
marketing, targeted advertising and data deletion; improving phishing warnings in email
clients; building and evaluating novel privacy controls for smart speakers.

${\bf 09/2016-} \qquad {\bf Illinois\ Informatics\ Institute}, {\bf Champaign,\ IL}.$

05/2017 Research Fellow. *Advisor: Masooda Bashir.*

• Investigated social and psychological factors in users' debate on Twitter regarding controversial topics. Duties included annotating tweets, analyzing survey data, and creating visualization dashboards.

04/2016- College of Media, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, IL.

05/2017 Research Fellow. *Advisor: Mike Yao, Michelle Nelson.*

- Assisted with an online experiment on bystanders' attitude toward cyberbullying cases.
- Assisted with a user study on content branded in virtual reality technology across various devices.

09/2015- Center for Innovation in Teaching and Learning, UIUC, Champaign, IL.

05/2017 Data Analytics Intern. *Advisor: Maryalice Wu*.

- Analyzed survey data for UIUC's Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs).
- Provided assistance to clients regarding survey question writing, sampling methodology, pilot testing, statistical analyses, and report writing.

Invited Talks

- [T5] An Empirical Analysis of Data Deletion and Opt-Out Choices on 150 Websites
 USENIX Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (SOUPS), Santa Clara, CA, USA, August 13, 2019.
- [T4] Lengthy, Vague, and Inactionable: Issues with Data Breach Notifications and Implications for Public Policy

The Federal Trade Commission's 4th annual PrivacyCon, Washington D.C., USA, June 27, 2019.

- [T3] **An Empirical Analysis of Readability and Usability Issues in Data Breach Notifications** ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (**CHI**), Glasgow, UK, May 7, 2019.
- [T2] Designing Effective and Actionable Data Breach Notices: Implications for Firefox Monitor Mozilla, Firefox Monitor. Mountain View, CA, USA, November 14, 2018.
- [T1] "I've Got Nothing to Lose": Consumers' Risk Perceptions and Protective Actions after the Equifax Data Breach

USENIX Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security (**SOUPS**), Baltimore, MD, USA, August 14, 2018.

Media Coverage

- [P3] Companies Send Confusing Alerts About Data Breaches Laurel Thomas, futurity.org, May 19, 2019.
- [P2] Freezing Credit Will Now Be Free. Here's Why You Should Go for It. Ann Carrns, New York Times, September 14, 2018.
- [P1] Credit freeze: A Misunderstood Freebie That You Actually Want
 Susan Tompor, Detroit Free Press, September 6, 2018. (Reprinted by over 80 regional and local media outlets)

Undergraduate/Master Student Research Advising

Year	Name	Placement
2019-present	Jamie Lai (SI Undergrad)	-
2019-present	Michael Ni (CS Undergrad)	-
2018	Kaiwen Sun (SI Master)	Ph.D. student, University of Michigan
2018	Shawn Danino (SI Master)	Policy Research Lead, Building Matters Ann Arbor
2018	Austin McCall (SI Undergrad)	Advisory Consultant, Deloitte

Teaching Experience

Fall 2019 Contextual Inquiry (SI 501), University of Michigan

Teaching assistant duties included grading assignments, holding office hours, and mentoring students about semester-long projects with clients.

Fall 2018 Introduction to Information (SI 110), University of Michigan

Teaching assistant duties included assisting with the preparation of course materials, leading two weekly discussion sections, holding office hour and grading. Also gave a guest lecture on information regulations and privacy.

Service

External

Program Committee:

• IEEE PerCom Workshop on Context Systems Design, Evaluation and Optimization (CoSDEO): 2020

Invited External Reviewer:

• Proceedings on Privacy Enhancing Technologies (PoPETs): 2019

• ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI): 2019

Department

Mentoring:

• Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program: 2019-2020

• UMSI Peer Mentorship Program: 2018-2020

Organizing:

· University of Michigan Privacy Day: 2020

Skills

Quantitative Methods Survey, Experiment, Log analysis

Qualitative Methods Interview, Participatory design, Usability testing, Content analysis

Statistical AnalysisR, SPSS, Microsoft ExcelSurvey DesignQualtrics, SurveyGizmo

Qualitative Coding ATLAS.ti, NVivo

Programming Languages Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Languages Mandarin (native), English (full proficiency)

Relevant Coursework

Theory-focused Doctoral Foundations Seminar in Information (SI 701)

Algorithmic Culture (SI 710)

Science, Technology, and Society (SI 719)

Consumer Behavior (MKT 898)

Method-focused Research Methods (SI 840)

Qualitative Methods (SI 724)

Statistical Methods (PSYCH 613, PSYCH 614)

Experimental Methods (SI 860)